<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Jason Havill</title>
    <link>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Jason Havill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 17:20:55 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jasonhavill.com/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Print</title>
      <link>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/print/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 21:47:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/print/</guid>
      <description>PrintOutputThe easiest way for a program to display output to the user is to print out text to the screen. The print function accomplished this by printing whatever is passed to it to the console.
The HowA print function is called just like any other function, with the name of the function followed by opening and closing parenthesis  print() .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strings</title>
      <link>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 22:14:03 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/strings/</guid>
      <description>StringsA string is a data type that stores a series (or &#34;string&#34;) of characters. These characters could make up a word, a sentence, or even entire paragraphs. The HowA string is denoted by surrounding characters in either single  &#39;&#39;  or double  &#34;&#34;  quotes.
myString = &#34;This is a string denoted with double quotes&#34;myOtherString = &#39;This is also a string, instead denoted with single quotes&#39;The variable name can then be used in place of the string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>if-else</title>
      <link>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/if-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 20:34:33 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/if-else/</guid>
      <description>If ElseAn if else statement is what allows a program to respond in real time to outside input. With these statements, the program can change what code is executed based on variables within the program.
The WhyWithout if else statements every program would run identically every time, severely restricting its usefulness. It is these statements which allow a calculator to deal with dividing by zero, a website to validate login credentials, and a game to discover when a shot has landed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tuples</title>
      <link>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/tuples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 20:34:33 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasonhavill.com/articles/tuples/</guid>
      <description>TuplesA tuple is a data type which stores other data types in an ordered index. For example, a tuple can store integers, floats, strings, and even other tuples. You cannot add to or remove data from a tuple once it has been created.
The HowJust as a string is denoted by surrounding characters in quotes
my_string = &#34;some text&#34;Tuples are created by surrounding data in round brackets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>